mtvbase.com 2013-06-08

# Privacy Policy| Info | MTV Base

**Who We Are**

This document sets out the privacy policy of MTV Networks Africa a wholly owned susbidiary of MTV Networks BV Europe and belonging to the Viacom group of companies. This policy explains how MTV Networks Africa and its affiliated companies ("we", "us", "our" or "the MTV group" use your personal information (meaning any information about you which is personally identifiable like your name, address, telephone number or email address and is generally referred to throughout this policy as "your information"). It applies to personal information collected from you. 

**How We Collect and Use Your Personal Information**

**General**

We collect your personal information in two ways: Firstly, when you give it to us (for example, when you provide information about yourself on an online form when participating in a competition or promotion). We use this information to process requests or orders, to enter you for competitions or promotions which you have indicated you wish to enter, to identify your personal preferences and to match your needs with relevant services or products. Secondly, when you register for our services using our registration services. The information you provide to us via online registration is used to provide you with access via your user name and password to our website(s), to enable you to enter competitions on the website(s) using your user name and password, to post messages on the message board, to sign up to receive newsletters and to set up a personal profile on the website(s). 

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

In addition and with your consent we (and if applicable, our partners or other trusted third parties) use your information for certain marketing, market research, analysis and related purposes. It is up to you how much or how little information you allow us to use for these purposes. Our on screen notices will ask for your explicit permission for such additional purposes. These purposes include:

\- to communicate with you from time to time by email and (where you provide us with those details either via the website(s) or elsewhere) by mobile (using SMS or, if your mobile device permits, MMS messages or similar technologies) and occasionally by post, with information, offers and other material which may interest you; 

\- to make your information available from time to time to trusted partners and third parties, for the same purposes as above;

\- to conduct market research, for example by asking you to participate in a survey about topical issues conducted by us or trusted partners or third parties. We will always try to tell you before you participate in the survey how any information you provide in the survey will be used; or 

\- to enable us and third parties acting on our behalf to analyse your information, in a non-identifying form, (generally in the form of statistics), so that we can identify trends about usage of our website(s) or services and improve them. Additionally we reserve the right to access and disclose your personal information in order to comply with applicable laws, to comply with lawful requests from governments, law enforcement agencies or parties whose request we reasonably consider to be justified in connection with any allegations by any party about your abuse of our services, to operate our systems properly or to protect ourselves or our users. 

**Automatic Information**

Like many websites, we use "cookies"; Cookies are small text files that websites automatically save to the cookie file of the browser on your computer when you enter the website. We do not use cookies that access any information stored on your hard drive or damage or otherwise endanger your computer. We use cookies to identify your computer when you visit the website(s) and to track and assist your navigation around the website(s). Examples of the information that may be collected and analysed using cookies are user-name, email address and password, the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, browser type and version, operating system and platform you use to connect, areas of the website(s) you viewed or searched for, the Uniform Resource Locators (URLs) from or through which you entered and exited our website(s) and the date and time of such activity. You can use the "Help" section of the tool bar on most browsers to change the settings on your computer, for example to notify you when you receive a cookie, or to refuse all cookies. However, some of the features of our website(s) may not work or may be more difficult to access if you refuse all cookies. We use a third party advertising company to serve advertisements on our website(s). This company may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visit to the website(s) in order to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. In the course of serving advertisements on the website(s), our third party advertiser may place or recognise a unique "cookie" on your browser. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by this company please click here: www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy 

**Unsubscribing/ Amending your information**

You can amend or remove information you give us via our website(s) at any time. If you want to amend your profile on the website(s) or remove your information from an SMS/MMS, newsletter or other distribution list which you subscribed to on the website(s), you can click on the "Update Profile" link when logged in on the website(s) and amend your profile accordingly. Alternatively, you may unsubscribe from a newsletter or other email distribution list by clicking on the relevant link on the newsletter/other email (which can normally be found at the bottom of the communication). You may withdraw from an SMS/MMS service you requested via SMS/MMS (as opposed to online) by following the instructions you receive in the message confirming your request. Any message requesting withdrawal from a service will be charged at standard rates. If you want to remove all of your information from our database, you may do so by sending an email to info@mtvbase.com specifying your name, user-name, email address and telephone number. In order to subsequently re-subscribe with the same user name, you will also need to email info@mtvbase.com. You may send any questions you may have about privacy issues via email to info@mtvbase.com 

**Security**

We have taken steps to ensure that your information is secure, including limiting the number of people who have physical access to our database servers, as well as electronic security systems and password protections that guard against unauthorised access. 

**Business Transfers**

In the unlikely event that we sell or otherwise dispose of some or all of our business to another party, we reserve the right to transfer your information as part of any assets sold or disposed of. 

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

We will try to email you if there are any changes to this policy that materially affect how we use your information. However, we encourage users to be responsible about their privacy and to check this policy from time to time and to update their preferences. 

This policy was last updated on 19 August 2008.
